# **Preeti Goel**

## SOFTWARF FNGINFFR

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/preeti-goel-5336b2199/

https://github.com/preetigoel10/

#### **≅** SYNOPSIS

I am a passionate software developer with 2.6 years of professional experience working in Hotels Technology Development for India's largest online travel company. I am equipped with the right blend of technical and behavioural competencies required in a modern digital era with a belief to help and serve the community at a global level.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MakeMyTrip Pvt. Ltd.

04/2021 - 12/2022

In my role of backend developer in **Hotels Technology Department** I've:

- Developed micro-services to serve the backend data efficiently and to make the application scalable.
- Introduced contextualization of the customer experience in the Hotels Funnel.
- Led the project to produce Group Booking feature for B2C funnel.
- Collaborated in unification of MMT-GI code base.

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN, MakeMyTrip Pvt. Ltd.** 07/2020 – 03/2021

In my role as android front-end developer for four months and as a java backend developer for five months I've worked on:

- Understanding the customer's problem's and coding, designing and collaborating to create solutions.
- Debugging project bugs and rewriting the code efficiently.

## ஐ TRAININGS

# 'Pre Education Program (PEP-2020)' by EPAM Systems India Pvt Ltd

01/2020 - 06/2020

Full Stack Web Application Development using Angular and Spring framework

07/2019 - 07/2019

Certified by Coursera in AWS Fundamentals Specialization

#### **EDUCATION**

#### MS in Computer Science, University of Southern California

01/2023 - 12/2024 | Los Angeles, USA

### B. E. (CSE), Chitkara University Institute of Engineering and Technology

2021 | Punjab, India

# Class XII, Guru Nanak Khalsa Senior Secondary School 2017 | Chandigarh, India

#### Class X. Carmel Convent School

2015 | Chandigarh, India

### PROJECTS

#### BlogPost - A Blog Website ∂

Technologies used: Angular 7, Spring framework, SQL database

#### **ShoppingBee - An E-commerce Website**

Technologies used: Angular 7, Spring framework, SQL database

#### Account Book - An Android application ∅

Language: Kotlin | Database: Room Database | Architecture: MVVM

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages** (C, C++, JAVA (Advanced), Python, Swift, Kotlin)

**API architecture** (gRPC, REST services)

**Front-end Development** (HTML5, CSS, PHP, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Android Development)

Frameworks (Angular 7, Spring Boot, Apache Kafka)

**DBMS** (MySQL, Oracle 11g, Couchbase, Redis, MongoDB)

**Application Software** (Cisco packet tracer, Umlet, Arduino)

**Version Control** (Git) • **OS** (Windows, Linux) • **Docker** 

**Linux Scripting** • **Proficient in Graphana** 

# AWARDS

#### **PROFESSIONAL**

- Received Go-Tripper award for the month of August 2022.
- Awarded with Ace Award for Quarter 2 (July-Sept'21) at MakeMyTrip Pvt. Ltd.

## **₩** BEHAVIORAL SKILLS

- Prefer Social Intelligence over emotional quotient
- Eager to learn and grow professionally.
- Achievement Oriented Thinking

# **&** LANGUAGES

English (TOEFL: 104)

**French** (Won Silver Medals in French Olympiad twice for consecutive years at school level.)

Hindi